A Guide to the Stone Family Papers, 1786-1860
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Stone Family Papers, 1786-1860
Library of Virginia
30815
1.85 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary Carter Stone, 12 October 1979.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Stone family were residents of Pittsylvania County, Virginia. James Hoskin Stone was born in Halifax County on 17 October 1778. He married Elizabeth Fitzgerald (1785-1865) of Pittsylvania County in 1803. They had 11 children. James Hoskin Stone was a Baptist minister, and preached at Old Shockoe Church for fifteen years. He died on 13 October 1854. His son, Edmund Stone, was born on 8 January 1805. He married Nancy Chapman Dickerson (1809-1851) on 1 February 1827. They had 9 children. Edmund Stone died on 20 October 1840. After his death, the guardianship of his young children went to his father, James Hoskin Stone.
Scope and Content Information
Papers, 1786-1860, of the Stone family of Pittsylvania County, Virginia. The majority of the papers relate to James Hoskin Stone (1778-1854) and his son Edmund Stone (1805-1840). Includes mainly accounts and receipts, deeds, estate papers, guardian's accounts, tax bills and receipts, as well as other items. There is a considerable amount of material relating to the guardianship of Edmund Stone's children by their grandfather.
Contents List
- Accounts and Receipts, 1806-1860 (Box 1, Folder 1-49)
- Accounts and Receipts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Account Book, 1831-1836 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Account Book, 1837-1849 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Arithmetic Book (includes Guardian's Accounts), 1841-1844 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Articles of Agreement (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Bonds (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Clerk's Fee Bills, 1834-1852 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1814-1849 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Deeds, 1786-1824 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Deeds, 1825-1846 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Estate of John A. Clark, 1843-1849 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Estate of William Hoskins, 1788-1808 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Estate of Edmund Stone, 1836-1845 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
- Estate of John Stone, 1824-1825 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Guardian's Accounts - Clack Stone (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Guardian's Accounts - Dolly Stone (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Guardian's Accounts - Elizabeth W. Stone (Edwards) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Guardian's Accounts - Elvira Stone (Edwards) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Guardian's Accounts - James C. Stone (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Guardian's Accounts - Mary A. Stone (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Guardian's Accounts - Nancy C. Stone (Goggin) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Guardian's Accounts - Sarah E. Stone (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Guardian's Accounts - William D. Stone (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Guardian's Accounts - Miscellaneous, 1841-1846 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Guardian's Accounts - Miscellaneous, 1847-1853 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Guardian's Accounts Book, 1843-1853 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Lists of Slaves (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Marriage Consent, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Military Pension of Samuel Johnson, 1818 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Minister's License (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Orders for Payment of Goods (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Poetry (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Powers of Attorney (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Promissory Notes (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Religious Writings (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Relinquishment of Dower, 1822, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Sheriff's Fee Bills (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Slave Bills of Sale, 1806-1846 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Suit Papers (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Surveys, 1808-1836 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Tax Bills and Receipts (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Will of James H. Stone, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Will of John Stone, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Oversize - Deeds, 1801-1830 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Oversize - Land Grants, 1787, 1805 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Oversize - Surveys, 1836-1848 (Box 4, Folder 3)